【家长提示】本片的评级为 TV-14-V，可能包含暴力等内容，
因而不建议 14 岁以下儿童独自观赏。
50年过去了
50 years have passed,
我的年岁却没有跟着增长
but I do not age.
时间  再无撼动我一丝一毫
Time has lost its effect on me.
折磨  却从未停止
Yet the suffering continues.
阿蛊的魔爪扼住了过去
Aku's grasp chokes the past,
现在  乃至未来
present, and future.
希望已然消逝
Hope is lost.
必须回去
Gotta get back,
回到过去
back to the past.
杰克武士
Samurai Jack.
Translated by @SerCom_KC
OPEN TRANSLATION PROJECT
翻译版本  v1.0.0-CHS
翻译  妙挖種子
你确定是她？
Are you sure she was the one?
校对  SerCom_KC
没错  我看她到处在问他的事情
Yes. I specifically saw her asking about him.
莫非是阿蛊手下的赏金猎人？
Aku's bounty hunter?
邪气好重啊
I sense her evil.
抓到了！
Gotcha!
我们不会让你伤害武士的
We will not let you hurt the Samurai.
伤害？
Hurt?
不  我…
No, I...
听着  我不是想伤害他
Look, I'm not trying to hurt him.
我是在找他
I'm trying to find him.
他可能出事了
He might be in trouble.
你是他的朋友吗？
You are his friend?
我…说不清
I... don't know.
我们是他的朋友
We are his friends.
那是很久很久以前的事情了
It was long ago.
那时的我们被当作奴隶使唤
We were slaves.
※补番指南：第肆集（EPISODE IV: Jack, the Woolies, and the Chritchellites）
给我老实点  你这没用的畜生！
Down, down, you miserable beast!
给我走！
Now go!
快点！给我走快点！
Come on! You're not moving fast enough.
但有一天  杰克来了
But then Jack came.
他拼尽全力解救我们
He risked his life to save ours.
小姐  你刚刚问的那个长着大胡子的家伙…
Miss, the bearded fella you inquired about...
他是在这里下去的
he got off here.
谢谢你们跟我说了这些
Thank you for sharing your story.
别还没落地就下去啊！
You're supposed to get off when you land!
我还活着！
I'm alive!
Doo do do do!
♪我还活着♪
♪ I'm alive ♪
噢  对哦！
Oh, right!
那个笨蛋武士把我的手机搞坏了
That samurai schmuck broke my phone.
我得把小杰杰丢了剑这事儿告诉阿蛊
I got to tell Aku that Jacky boy lost his sword.
哎妈呀  看来我得一路跳过去了
Oh, well, I guess I'm bunny hopping my way there.
蹦跶蹦跶
Hippity hop, baby!
汝若是阿蛊之人  还请速速离开此地
If you are one of Aku's minions, we suggest you run.
否则  报上名号来
If you are another, then reveal yourself.
我是来找那个武士的
I seek the Samurai.
不  我是为了帮他
No, I seek to help him.
他可能有危险
He might be in danger.
杰克武士之友亦是吾辈之友
A friend of Samurai Jack is a friend of ours.
跟我来
Come.
这里就是我们的家园
Welcome to our home.
如果没有他  就没有这样的今天
None of this would exist if it wasn't for him.
我们曾是诅咒之人
We were cursed...
※补番指南：第柒集（EPISODE VII: Jack and the Three Blind Archers）
看守着一个魔法传送门
bound to guard a magical portal.
武士本可斩杀我们
The Samurai was able to defeat us,
但他并未用以许下私愿
but instead of using it to fulfill his quest...
而是选择了解救我们
he freed us.
如此伟大的无私之举
An act of unmeasurable sacrifice.
日后  我们方知  诅咒乃阿蛊所为
Later, we learned the curse was of Aku's doing.
你们有看见过他吗？
Have you seen him?
他有经过这里吗？
Has he passed through here?
没有  自那天起  我们再未见到他的身影
No. Since that day, we have not seen him.
但我们依旧选择与阿蛊对抗
But we now stand against Aku.
我们愿意为他挺身而出
If he is ever in need, we will be there.
谢谢
Thank you.
我得走了
I have to go.
噢  老天
Oh, man.
这样走路真是伤脖子
Oh. All this walking is hard on my neck.
嘿  我到了！
Hey, I made it!
我终于到了！
I finally made it!
Aah!
闹哪样啊这是？
What is the problemo, babe?
无衣  无鞋  无身  勿入？！
"No shirt, no shoes, no body -- no entry"?!
哎呀妈呀
Swing-a-ding-ding!
我可是阿蛊最顶尖的机器人
I am Aku's top bot,
刺客中的辞人
the assassin with the sassin'.
阿蛊顶尖刺客排名
"Aku's current top assassins --
第一名  死之吹息
one, Deathblow,
第二名  大爆弹
two, Da-Bomb,
第三名  无情懦夫？！
three, Scaramouche"?!
妈呀  我被挤下来了哇
Oh, baby, I have come down in the world.
不知道你们会怎么想
How do you like that?
前一天  你还是高高在上的巨星
One day, you're the star of the show,
转眼间就被两个名不见经传的家伙挤到了板凳上
the next, you're the third act of a two-act play.
讲道理  站在这里的巨星才是头号
Well, this star is a headliner, babe,
而且只要我把小杰杰丢了剑儿这事告诉阿蛊
and once I tell Aku Jacky-o lost his sword-o,
第一名就又是咱个儿的啦
I'll be numero uno once more-o.
嗯  问题是要怎么上那艘…
Hmm, now how am I gonna get aboard the...
欸  中奖了  好起！
Oh, bing-o, baby!
啊  真是有够烦
Oh, drat!
汪汪汪
Bow wow wow!
汪汪汪个儿汪！
Bow wow wow, babe!
（禁狗）
汪汪被虐了
Bow wow heartbreaker.
欸  这身就很靓了
Yeah, babe. Dig this groovy cat.
喔  喔  哦呀  喔  喔  轻松飘过
Chow, chow, chowdity-chow chow, baby cakes!
哇！第一名  我来啦！
Whoo-hoo! Numero uno, here I come!
老兄  说好的50块
That's 50 credits, bud.
你就相信我吧  准没错
Trust me, babe, I'm good for it.
是吗  上次我信了某个人  结果中了这个邪
Yeah, well the last guy I trusted did this to me!
没事的啦  大兄弟
Oh, it's all good, Babou.
只要我跟阿蛊说一声  肯定要什么有什么
Aku will give me anything once he hears the news.
♪ Doo doo doo doo ♪
哇  那货是真奇葩
Whoa, what a freak.
简直就一会说话的鸡巴
Looked like a talking penis.
你们有看到过一个武士经过这里吗？
Have you seen a samurai come through here?
你要对武士干什么？
What do you want with the Samurai?
我感觉他有危险
I think he's in danger.
他需要我的帮助
He needs my help.
切武士之歌！
Samurai drop!
※补番指南：第贰拾捌集（EPISODE XXVIII: Jack and the Rave）
♪ 你的身影  我们此生难以忘怀 ♪
♪ We will never forget you till the day we die ♪
♪ 武士哟 ♪
♪ Samurai ♪
♪ 武  武  武士哟 ♪
♪ Sa-sa-samurai ♪
♪ 阿蛊用那地狱旋律 ♪
♪ Aku enslaved the children ♪
♪ 奴役着孩子们 ♪
♪ with his beats from hell ♪
♪ 然而那人与邪恶战斗到底 ♪
♪ But then he came and fought the evil away ♪
♪ 是那个武士 ♪
♪ It was the Samurai ♪
♪ 那个武士 ♪
♪ The Samurai ♪
♪ 你的身影  我们此生难以忘怀 ♪
♪ We will never forget you till the day we die ♪
♪ 武士哟 ♪
♪ Samurai ♪
♪ 武  武  武士哟 ♪
♪ Sa-sa-samurai ♪
♪ 武士哟… ♪
♪ Samurai -- ♪
谢谢你们
Thank you.
我会找到他的
I will find him.
我一定要找到他
I must find him.
阿蛊  吾主之主
Aku, our lord and master,
与黑暗同在
is one with the darkness.
诞生于黑暗之中
He was born from it.
赋予他无穷之力
It fills him with infinite power.
我们亦应与之融为一体
We, too, must become one with it.
能服侍您是我们此生最大的荣幸
We are forever grateful and ever in your service.
Uh-oh.
嘿  宝贝  行行好  帮我拿杯喝的来
Hey, babe, be a doll and fetch us a drinky-poo.
滚开  死混球
Screw off, jerkhead!
我才不是服务生
I don't work here!
真是玻璃心
Oh, touchy.
电话！
A phone!
不愧是无情懦夫  幸运鬼附身啊
Scaramouche, you are one lucky devil.
这边是话务员  请问有什么可以帮到您？
This is the operator. Can I help you?
帮我接一下阿蛊好嘛  对方付费
Yeah, emergency collect call to Aku, babe.
请说出您的名字
Please say your name.
♪ 无情懦夫 ♪
♪ Scaramouche ♪
请稍等
Please hold.
喂？
Hello?
对方付费来电  来电人
Collect call from...
♪ 无情懦夫 ♪
♪ Scaramouche ♪
您愿意支付费用吗？
Will you accept the charges?
Oh, uh...
Eh...
好吧
I guess.
谢谢你
Thank you.
阿蛊  我的老大
Aku, my boss-man,
我有一个天大的好消息  信不信由你
you will not believe what I just went through, babe.
什么？
What?!
根本听不清！
It's hard to hear you!
呃  等我一下
Eh, hold on a sec.
嘿  老兄们  你们可不可以  就是  小声点？
Hey, fellas, could you keep it, like, down?
我在通电话呢
I'm trying to have a conversation.
你在说我们吗？
You talking to us?
对啊  咋了  流浪狗
Yeah, that's right, rover.
就算是汪汪汪也给我小点声儿
I want you to keep your barking to a minimum.
流浪狗？
Rover?
汪汪汪？
Barking?
难不成他把我们当狗了？
I think he's calling us dogs.
嗨呀  小狗狗们  不服就去照照镜子啊
Okay, little puppy, you looked in a mirror lately?
给我滚一边儿去  去叼你们主人的拖鞋之类的
Now, go get somebody their slippers or something.
我这边打着电话呢
I'm on the line.
是这样的  阿蛊  咱亲爱的小杰杰把剑…
So I wanted to tell ya, Aku, Jacko has lost --
哈？什么？
Huh? What?
啊  算了
Forget it!
放在平常的话  俺们就会把你的头给拧下来了
Usually me and the boys would rip your head from your body,
不过看来有人比我们快了一步啊
but looks like somebody already did us the favor, eh?
既然这样的话…
So in lieu of that...
真是肛了狗了
Dippity doo dang, babe.
喂  那边的  把门带上！
Hey, man, close the damn door!
热气全给你散完了！
You're letting all the heat out!
来这儿干嘛的  树叶女孩？
What you want here, Leaf Girl?
我在找杰克武士
I'm looking for Samurai Jack.
哈？你刚刚说啥？
Huh, what'd you say?
我在找杰克武士
I'm looking for Samurai Jack.
哈？你到底在说啥？
Huh? What's that?
妈的  妹子  说大点声！
Damn it, girl, speak up!
我在找杰克武士！
I'm looking for Samurai Jack!
你在找那个武士？
You're looking for the Samurai?!
杰克武士那个死混蛋  骨头可硬了  小丫头
Little girl, Samurai Jack is the toughest S.O.B. out there.
上次跟他打  他把我整成了…
Last time we fought, he did...
这样
this to me.
哈！那算什么？你看我！
Ha! That's nothing! Check me out!
不是我开玩笑  我可是靠这些东西一直坚持到现在
These things are literally holding me together!
不是吧  老兄
Dude, really?
我以前还能自己去厕所  但我现在只能靠小袋子
I used to go to the bathroom, but now I go in a bag!
他还把我眼睛给打爆了！
He busted me eye!
真是的  一个个就知道叫  你们哪个机器人能跟我比？
Man... those robotic cats got nothin' on me!
想当年  我还是个坏到爆的武士呢！
'Cause back in the day, I was a bad-ass sa-mu-rai!
人称“达武士”！
I was Da' Samurai!
※补番指南：第肆拾贰集（EPISODE XLII: Samurai vs. Samurai）
切切砍砍是我的菜
I was all about the slicing and dicing!
比如说…
Talkin' 'bout the...
潮流砍！
Funk-a-Chop!
怪力切！
The Whack-a-Hack!
以及我最得意的…
And, of course, the ever famous...
火鸡斩！
Turkey Carve!
但是杰克武士点醒了我
But Samurai Jack enlightened me
让我懂得了当一个武士真正的意义
to the true meaning of being a samurai.
在那之后  我把剑扔了  顶髻也不弄了
Shortly after, I gave up my blade and top knot
留在这个最初与他相遇的地方  当一个小酒保
and became the bartender here at the place where we first met.
呃…
Uh...
这算糟糕吗？
That doesn't sound bad at all.
你们这群没心没肺的蠢机器懂什么！
That's because you ain't got no soul, you robot fool!
我回来啦！
I have returned!
在下戴蒙戈  专门收集伟大战士们的灵魂
I, Demongo, have come to collect the souls of the greatest warriors.
※补番指南：第贰拾叁集（EPISODE XXIII: Jack vs. Demongo, The Soul Collector）
不过看来我来错地方了
But I see I have come to the wrong place.
来这里的老实鬼还真不少啊
We got some straight-up freaks coming through this place.
你是不是在寻找那个武士？
Are you the one looking for the Samurai?
是的
Yes.
你是他的朋友吗？
Are you his friend?
是的
Yes.
沿着路向北走
Follow the path north.
你…？
Who... ?
武士！
Samurai!
杰克？
Jack?
你可以在此见证  但决不得干涉
You may witness, but you cannot proceed any further.
见证什么？
Witness what?
末路
The end.
伟大战士的亡灵们啊  欢迎你们的到来
Great warriors of past, I welcome you.
这个武士没能遵守他的承诺
This samurai has failed his purpose
现在  他认清了自己的命运
and has accepted his fate.
住手！
Stop!
此事与你无关
This does not concern you.
他已经没有希望了
There is no hope.
不对！
No!
希望是有的
Hope lives.
到处都有
It is everywhere.
我看到了  那些与你接触过的人们
I've seen it, everyone you have touched,
那些你帮助过的人们
the people you have helped.
是你拯救了他们啊！
You saved them!
够了！
Enough!
希望不过是一种转瞬即逝的感情
Hope is just a fleeting sentiment.
你的失败已是事实
Your failure is real.
要么直面这个结果
You must face the consequences
要么继续背负这耻辱的罪名  直到永恒
or continue to bear the guilt of your dishonor for all eternity.
杰克  别听他的！
Jack, don't listen!
事情不是他说的那样！
You're being misguided!
我都看到了
I've seen it.
你救下的无辜之人数不胜数
You've saved countless innocents.
而且最重要的是…
And most of all...
你让我看清了真相！
you showed me the truth!
你带我进入了一个更加广阔的世界
You made me see that there's so much more to me than I knew existed.
你让我超越了曾经的自己
You made me way more than what I was.
拯救我的希望之人  正是你啊！
The hope you gave me saved my life!
你所到之处  生灵涂炭
Death follows in your wake --
男人  女人  小孩  无一幸免
men, woman, children.
没错
Yes.
那些死去的孩子  都是你的罪过
All those children dead because of you.
不对！
No!
那些孩子  他们还活着！
The children -- they're alive!
你救了他们！
You saved them!
给我闭嘴！
No more words!
我…
I, uh...
我觉得你的发型不错
I like your hair.
衣服也是
And dress.
现在怎么办？
What now?
是时候找回我的剑了
It's time to find my sword.
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Gotta get back ♪
♪ Back to the past ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪
第玖拾柒集
♪ Gotta get back, back to the past, Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Gotta get back ♪
♪ Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪